Guide to the Richard C. Jeffrey Papers, 1934-2002 ASP.2003.02
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Writings, Lectures, and Publications, 1952-2002; IV.
  - Editorial Work: Hempel's Selected Philosophical Essays, 1934-2000; 3.
    - Galley Proofs
      - Chapters 1-5, 1999 (Box 25, Folder 4)
      - Chapters 6-8, 1999 (Box 25, Folder 5)
      - Chapters 9-12, 1999 (Box 25, Folder 6)
      - Chapters 13-16, 1999 (Box 25, Folder 7)
      - Chapters Hempel's Publication and Index, 1999 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Related Material to Edition of Selected Philosophical Essays
      - Entry on Hempel by Jeffrey for Routledge Encyclopedia of Philosophy, and Correspondence, 1996 (Box 25, Folder 9)
      - Cambridge University Press Marketing for Hempel's Selected Philosophical Essays, 2000 (Box 25, Folder 10)
      - Hempel-Neurath Correspondence: Copies and Excerpts, 1934-1935 (Box 25, Folder 11)
      - Copy of Hempel's Published PhD Thesis with Annotations by Jeffrey (Box 25, Folder 12)
      - Copies of Hempel's Writings, 1937-1981 (Box 25, Folder 13)
      - Copy of Hempel's "Postcript 1976: More Recent Ideas on the Problem of Statistical Explanation." (Box 25, Folder 14)
      - Interview with Hempel by Richard Nollan with Corrections, 1982-1983 (Box 26, Folder 1)
      - "Methodology of Science: Descriptive and Prescriptive Facets", Typescript of Hempel's Lecture at Tel Aviv University, 1984 (Box 26, Folder 2)
      - "Hempel and the Vienna Circle", Typescript of Article by Michael Friedman (Box 26, Folder 3)
      - Copies of Writings by Hempel for Edition of Selected Philosophical Essays (Box 26, Folder 04-08)
- Teaching, 1959-1997; V.
  The majority of documents consist of sylllabi, reading lists, exams, and some correspondence. Included are also transcriptions of Jeffrey's 1985 Stanford Lectures by M. Hendrickson. If present, folders are grouped according to their class number with an overall chronological arrangement, starting with the earliest.
  - Examinations, Readings, and Assignments for Various Courses, some by Hempel, 1959-1979 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Phil. 166: Probability and Induction, Stanford University, 1960-1962 (Box 27, Folder 02-03)
  - City College New York, 1964-1965 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Phil. 6/606, 1969-1972 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Phil. 375: Decision Theory, 1972-1977 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Phil. 375: Probability and Scientific Inference, 1978-1994 (Box 27, Folder 7-10)
  - Phil. 521: Probability and Induction, 1973 (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Phil. 531: Probability and Confirmation, 1976 (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Phil. 531: Philosophy of Science, 1982 (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Phil. 531: Probability and the Art of Judgement, 1986 (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - Phil. 201: Introductory Logic, 1977-1994 (Box 27, Folder 15-16)
  - Phil. 313: Theory of Knowledge, 1983-1995 (Box 27, Folder 17-19)
  - Phil. 204: Introduction to the Philosophy of Science, 1984-1985 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Leave for Standford, Correspondence, 1984 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Phil. 163: Probability and Induction, Stanford University: Syllabus, Lecture Notes, Readings, 1984-1985 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Phil. 163: Transcriptions of Jeffrey's Stanford Lectures by M. Hendrickson, 1985 (Box 28, Folder 04-05)
  - Phil. 533: Decision Theory, Background and Recent Developments, 1991-1995 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Phil. 312: Intermediate Logic, 1992-1993 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Phil. 372: Philosophical Foundations of Game and Decision Theory, 1993 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Phil. 211: Course Material, 1995 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Phil. 373: Probabilistic Thinking, 1996 (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Phil. 273: Probabilistic Judgement, 1997 (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Teaching Notes on Elementary Probability Calculus, Dutch Book Argument, Probability Kinematics, and Probability and Utility, undated (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Course Material on Evolutionary Biology, undated (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Phil. 513: The Career of Logical Positivism: Syllabus, Notes, and Readings, undated (Box 29, Folder 01-10)
  - Recorded Lectures by Jeffrey on 25 Cassette Tapes, undated (Box 29a, Cassette unknown container)
- Writings by Others, VI.
  Documents comprised in this series are unpublished manuscript drafts or annotated published writings by authors other than Jeffrey, many of whom were friends or collaborators, such as Brian Skyrms and Bruno de Finetti. In addition to annotations, a few pieces include more extensive written comments by Jeffrey.
  The folders are arranged alphabetically, according to the author's last name.
  - Ax, James and Simon Kochen (Box 29a, Folder 11)
  - Ballentine, L. E. (Box 29a, Folder 12)
  - Bar-Hillel, Maya (Box 29a, Folder 13)
  - Biersdorfer, J. D. (Box 29a, Folder 14)
  - Blyth, Colin R. (Box 29a, Folder 15)
  - Bolker, Ethan (Box 29a, Folder 16)
  - Bradley, Richard (Box 29a, Folder 17)
  - Broome, John (Box 29a, Folder 18)
  - Carnap, Rudolf (Box 29a, Folder 19)
  - Caves, Carlton M., Christopher A. Fuchs, and Rüdiger Schack (Box 29a, Folder 20)
  - Cheeseman, Peter (Box 29a, Folder 21)
  - Davidson, Donald (Box 29a, Folder 22)
  - Davis, Martin (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Dawid, A. P. (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - De Finetti, Bruno (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Diaconis, Persi (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Diamond, Peter A. (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Dorling, Jon (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Earman, John (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Einstein, Albert, et. al. (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Elga, Adam (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Field, Hartry (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Franklin, Allan (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Friedman, Michael (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - Gaifman, Haim (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - Gardner, Martin (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - Goodman, Nelson (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - Hardy, Lucien (Box 30, Folder 16)
  - Harper, William (Box 30, Folder 17)
  - Hartle, J. B. (Box 30, Folder 18)
  - Hild, Matthias (Box 30, Folder 19)
  - Hosiasson-Lindenbaum, Janina (Box 30, Folder 20)
  - Isham, Chris J. (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Jaynes, E. T. (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Joyce, James M. (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Kassirer, Jerome P. (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Kawalec, Pawel (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Kempson, Richard L. and Michael R. Hendrickson (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - K., S. Jr. (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Kochen, Simon (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Koons, Robert C. (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Landsman, N. P. (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Launoir, Rue (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Leeds, Stephen (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - Leonhardt, David (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - Levi, Issac (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - Llinás, Rodolfo (Box 31, Folder 15)
  - Maudlin, Tim (Box 31, Folder 16)
  - McGee, Vann (Box 31, Folder 17)
  - Merin, Arthur (Box 31, Folder 18)
  - Mermin, David N. (Box 31, Folder 19)
  - Mongin, Philippe (Box 31, Folder 20)
  - Monton, Bradley (Box 31, Folder 21)
  - Moore, Michael B. (Box 31, Folder 22)
  - Neurath, Otto (Box 31, Folder 23)
  - Patton, Thomas E. (Box 31, Folder 24)
  - Pólya, George (Box 31, Folder 25)
  - Price, Huw (Box 31, Folder 26)
  - Rabinowicz, Wlodzimierz (Box 31, Folder 27)
  - Raiffa, Howard (Box 31, Folder 28)
  - Rastall, Peter (Box 31, Folder 29)
  - Real, Leslie A. (Box 31, Folder 30)
  - Ricketts, Thomas (Box 31, Folder 31)
  - Risse, Mathias (Box 31, Folder 32)
  - Rubinstein, Ariel (Box 31, Folder 33)
  - Schulman, Stuart (Box 31, Folder 34)
  - Schwartz, William B., et al. (Box 31, Folder 35)
  - Scott, Dana (Box 31, Folder 36)
  - Seidenfeld, Teddy (Box 31, Folder 37)
  - Selten, Reinhard, and Ulrike Leopold (Box 31, Folder 38)
  - Shafer, Glenn (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Shimony Abner (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Skyrms, Brian (Box 32, Folder 03-10)
  - Smith, Nicholas J. J. (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Sobel, Jordan Howard (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Steane, Andrew (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Strevens, Michael (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Van Fraassen, Bas C. (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Wagner, Carl G. (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Walliser, Bernard (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Wilson, N. L. (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Zadeh, L. A. (Box 33, Folder 8)